losif V.

Software Engineer

London, UK

in iosify 🞧 iosify 🚵 iosify

Hey there I'm losif, a senior Backend Engineer with experience in creating complete projects from start to finish in Node.js and PHP. I write code as clean as possible so that the next dev will be happy to maintain it and the junior will quickly grasp it. Curious by nature, I'm always willing to learn new things, so these days I spend my evenings working with Solidity and Hardhat on creating Blockchain smart contracts.

SKILLS -

Languages					Frameworks				Admin			
	Node.js	Typescript	PHP	Lar	ravel	Express	Serverless		AWS	Terraform	CI / CD	
	Solidity	bash		Har	Hardhat				Docker Shell Scripting			

WORK EXPERIENCE (9) -

Aug 2018 - Current

Software Engineer at Casa4

Contractor for various clients. Worked on diverse projects, specializing in PHP, Laravel, and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment.

- ElectroRent: Collaborated on a team of 20 developers on a complex tool-renting platform written in Laravel.
- Aliat Optic: Designed and produced an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB.
- The Hurlingham Club: Managed system migration to internal servers, resolving a wide range of dependancy and dev-ops issues.
- TicketTailor: Enhanced the API of a sophisticated PHP application with both bugfixes and new features.
- Green State State

Mar 2022 - Current

Information Technology Advisor at Artetra

Startup that works towards bringing NFT's into online virtual galleries.

- I am contributing within business meetings on the IT side of the project.
- Most of the time is spent on translating the business requirements into actual features of the project by managing a small team of 3-4 developers.
- By having a general view of the project, I can help anyone who is stuck at any point.
- → Technologies: Node.js, Hardhat, Solidity, AWS, Bash

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer at True Compliance

Cloud Based Compliance Management System.

- Worked on building the main API of the system. Contributed to all the adjacent applications which constituted the entire ecosystem deployed as serverless functions on AWS with Laravel Vapor. Involved in designing some parts of the ecosystem's architecture.
- Some notable projects were a full reporting application which would create a report from any SQL provided. A system to serve real time data faster to the end client; by saving all the processed relational data into a no-sql database thus providing instant access to the transformed client-friendly set of the data.
- Technologies: PHP 7, PHP 8, Laravel 8, Laravel 9, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Software Engineer at Skin Analytics

Designing and developing our main AI Skin Analytics applications and keeping an eye on the AWS infrastructure.

- Biggest task was a migration from a no-sql database to a relational database which resulted in a 11x speed increase. All this was achieved with 100% transparency to the end user.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

PHP Application Developer / Dev-Ops at Woooba

Designing, developing & supporting client applications.

- Developed & maintained nationwide educational platforms. Designed and integrated various APIs.
- We built a complete financial management application.
- Managed all our DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup.
- Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, PHP 5.6, PHP 7.1, RESTful APIs, MySql, Git, CLI, VueJS, PhpUnit.

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

PHP Application Developer at iQU Group

Marketing solutions for game developers.

- Created complete APIs from start to end as well as libraries which were used by my colleagues.
- Another smaller project was built with Java and PipelineDB.
- Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Symfony, API, MySQL, Git, Docker, CLI, PhpUnit, AngularJS, Java

Oct 2014 - Nov 2015

PHP Application Developer at Project 89109

Online adult dating services.

Technologies: PHP, API, MySQL, CLI, Git, JS, jQuery.

Nov 2017 - Current

Hardware Engineer / Dev-Ops at Hidden Hash (Personal Venture)

Family business dealing with mining crypto-currencies.

- Worked on Business model, Hardware setup, Software & security optimization/tweaks/updates,
 Performance fine tuning, Trading generated assets.
- Learned a lot about managing a larger than usual number of computers and hardware components.
- Built an open-source watchdog mechanism for certain types of graphic cards (https://github.com/iosifv/amd-vega-startup-scripts).

May 2005 - Dec 2014

Photographer at Saya Studio (Personal Venture)

Photography studio focusing mainly on weddings.

 Worked on Client handling, Marketing, Accounting, Management, Photographing, Retouching, Graphic design, Web-design.

PROJECTS (3) -

Terminal ToolBelt

https://github.com/iosifv/terminal-toolbelt

- Open source collection of aliases and bash functions which I use.
- Organised in something which resembles a CLI Framework.

Silence

Open source tool for safely backing up ssh keys in a git repository

iosifv.com

- A copy of the repository of my website.
- Backend management system written in Laravel. Includes a photo gallery, quotes collection and a really cool json generated CV.

EDUCATION (2) —

2010 - 2012

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

General management theories

2004 - 2009

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

C++	Java	.NET	SQL	Lisp	Prolog	Xilinx	Assembly	x86 processor	Electronics	Physics	
LANG	UAGES										
English			Romanian					Hungari			
Advanced			Native speaker					Beginner			

INTERESTS

Hobbies

Chess HiFi Music Photography

REFERENCES

" https://www.linkedin.com/in/iosifv/ "

Publicly available on LinkedIn